so I do not have cancer but there's so
many people in my life
Quinton says and family members my uncle
died this last year of cancer and his
wife years before I was born my
grandmother had cancer a few times
although she didn't I don't think she
really died from that she was 98 but
like there's two moms and a Facebook
group that I'm part of and although I've
never met them in person they're both
not right now beings give me five
minutes and one of them just got their
PET scans back and is it's growing and
the other one has already been told that
she's dying
this takes me so angry like cancer is
one of those things we can handle
together much more easily than it
currently is science being done in
secret science being done for profit
science being done for the politics of
it and all of the money all around the
world that's raised for cancer and we
are not doing what needs to get done
because quite frankly what needs to get
done is to stop the canary in the
coalmine stop all of the environmental
degradation is leading to all of the
cancers and to have genetics studies
done in a massive scale with voluntary
members people patients whatever
citizens human beings collecting our own
data and together figuring out like it's
so hard to navigate I've never been
diagnosed with cancer but I have been
diagnosed with brain tumors and
navigating the medical system the
Western and the alternative and all of
the conflicting advice within both of
them separate and definitely together
and everything you do is wrong if you
follow Western medicine it's wrong if
you follow of alternative medicine it's
wrong and if it works then you have like
it's you have this secret this like
powerful file that isn't a secret but it
was like
like no one believes you because we
don't own science together we act like
together we can understand science grate
it so that when you're if you're
diagnosed with cancer you don't need
your oncologist to tell you all the
options because you can see the options
you don't have to go with their bias and
what they're getting profit off of even
if it's not conscious profit like
they're not like if I do this I'm
getting a thousand dollars like oh wait
this is the people to pay my checks
these are the people that funded my my
grants whatever it happens to be I'm
going to describe this one this one's
new and different like biased it isn't
even about money they're just like oh
it's no so of course it's better not
necessarily and not different groups of
people and different kinds of cancer
like the only way we understand it is on
a massive scale the only way to
understand anything on a massive scale
is to collaborate is to have scientists
collaborate and everyday people being
able to understand it so that people who
are educated outside the box how you do
it themselves are able to give ideas as
they come up to be able to not have the
corporation's be in the hands of ever
it's like oh is it gonna make money even
no we don't want that we don't care
about the testing early we don't care
about the drugs we'd like if it's profit
driven if that's if they're not putting
their money into like okay why have our
cancers gone up well how do we actually
stop as many cancers from happening
they're not looking at that because
that's not where the money is the money
is in solving it once it happens and and
not even like curing it if it was cheap
they'd have to like have an ongoing and
hopefully causes chronic illness down
the road that we can we can sell you
something on and this is one of those
areas everyone is gonna benefit with I
don't care if you're the richest person
on the planet Steve Jobs died of cancer
all of his money in the world could not
save him and a cure could hey something
that we can actually assess together and
understand the science and break down
the hierarchy of doctor and patient
and collaborate on a massive scale
scientists all over the world because if
it's not done for profit and it's done
for purpose for actually fucking solving
cancer then um yeah we do a better job
that way I just want to do what I can to
help because I can't help those two I
know nothing but maybe they're kids